《美國殺人魔》
今晚的麵點是檸檬香草湯魷魚小方餃
Our pasta this evening is squid ravioli in a lemon grass broth...
還有羊乳甜餅和芝麻菜凱薩色拉
with goat cheese profiteroles, and I also have a rugula Caesar salad.
今晚的主菜是箭魚肉糜糕和洋蔥果醬
For entrees this evening, I have swordfish meatloaf with onion marmalade,
黑莓汁半熟烤鵪鶉脯和酸模夾心烤餡餅
rare roasted partridge breast in raspberry coulis with a sorrel timbale.
還有燒烤野兔肉 炸薯條做底
...and grilled free-range rabbit with herbed French fries.
今晚的麵點是檸檬香草湯魷魚小方餃
Our pasta tonight is squid ravioli in a lemon grass broth.
- 天哪 我討厭這地方 這是小娘們的餐廳 - 幹嗎不去朵西亞?
- God, I hate this place. It's a chick's restaurant. - Why aren't we at Dorsia ?
因為巴特曼和那兒的領班鬧彆扭
Because Bateman won't give the maitre d' head.
那邊的是裏德·羅賓遜嗎?
Is that Reed Robinson over there?
- 你是不是藥嗑多了? 那才不是羅賓遜呢 - 那麼是誰?
- Are you freebasing or what? That's not Robinson. - Well, who is it then?
- 是保羅·艾倫 - 不是吧
- It's Paul Allen. - That's not Paul Allen.
保羅·艾倫在屋子的另外一頭
Paul Allen's on the other side of the room over there.
- 他和誰在一起? - 從凱克瑟·皮博迪來的蠢貨
- Who's he with? - Some weasel from Kicker Peabody.
這兒連嗑藥的好點的洗手間都沒有
They don't have a good bathroom to do coke in.
- 你肯定那邊的是保羅·艾倫嗎? - 沒錯 麥克達菲思 我肯定
- Are you sure that's Paul Allen over there? - Yes, McDufus, I am.
- 他在做費希爾那單生意 - 走運的傢伙
- He's handling the Fisher account. - Lucky bastard.
- 走運的猶太傢伙 - 上帝啊 麥克德莫特 那有任何關係嗎?
- Lucky Jew bastard. - Jesus, McDermott, what does that have to do with anything?
我看到那傢伙在他辦公室裏
I've seen that bastard sitting in his office...
一面和總裁通電話 一面玩在轉他媽的燭台
talking on the phone to the C.E.O.s, spinnin' a fuckin' menorah.
不是燭台 他們轉的是陀螺
Not a menorah. You spin a dreidel.
哦 天哪 巴特曼
Oh, my God, Bateman.
你想讓我給你炸點馬鈴薯薄餅嗎? 土豆餅?
Do you want me to fry you up some fucking potato pancakes ? Some latkes ?
不 只是...少說兩句反猶太的話吧
No, just... cool it with the anti-Semitic remarks.
哦 我忘了 巴特曼在和美國公民自由協會的人約會呢
Oh, I forgot. Bateman's dating someone from the A.C.L.U.
他是理智的代言人 一個隔壁男孩
He's the voice of reason. The boy next door.
談到理智... 只要570塊
Speaking of reasonable... Only $570.
還不錯嘛
That's not bad.
稍微掏了點腰包
A little something for the purse.
給她50塊小費
Give her the 50.
" I used to think that the day would never come "
" I'd see the light the shade of the morning sun "
" My morning sun is the drug that brings me here "
" To the child lost replaced by fear "
" I used to think that the day would never come "
" That my life would begin to "
來杯"斯特利巖"
Stoli on the rocks.
這不能用了 這是付現金的酒吧
These aren't good anymore. It's a cash bar.
25塊錢
That'll be $25.
你他們的臭婊子
You're a fucking ugly bitch.
我要把你捅了
I wanna stab you to death...
再玩你的血
and play around with your blood.
兩位要什麼?
What can I get for you two ?
我住在在西81街
I live in the American Gardens building...
美國公園大廈十一樓
on West 81st Street on the 11th floor.
我叫帕特裏克·巴特曼
My name is Patrick Bateman.
現年27歲
I'm 27 years old.
我信奉自我養生
I believe in taking care of myself,
定量進餐 大量運動
in a balanced diet, in a rigorous exercise routine.
每天早晨 如果我的臉皮有點松
In the morning, if my face is a little puffy,
我會在做俯臥撐的時候上上冰袋
I'll put on an icepack while doing my stomach crunches.
我現在能做一千下了
I can do a thousand now.
除下冰袋後 我要用深層毛孔清潔露
After I remove the icepack, I use a deep pore cleanser lotion.
在沖澡的時候 我會上一種水洗凝膠清潔劑
In the shower, I use a water-activated gel cleanser.
然後是蜜煉杏仁磨砂沐浴露
Then a honey-almond body scrub.
再在臉上用去角質磨砂膠
And on the face, an exfoliating gel scrub.
接著我會做個薄荷草藥面膜
Then I apply an herb mint facial masque,
在等待的10分鐘里 我會為其他的日常程序做準備工作
which leave on for ten minutes while I prepare the rest of my routine.
我總上用不含或只含少量酒精的刮面後香露
I always use an aftershave lotion with little or no alcohol,
因為酒精會讓你的面部乾燥 看起來更老
because alcohol dries your face out and makes you look older.
然後是潤膚露
Then moisturizer,
然後是抗衰老眼霜
then an anti-aging eye balm,
最後是潤潤護膚露
followed by a final moisturizing protective lotion.
帕特裏克·巴特曼是一個意象
There is an idea of a Patrick Bateman.
很抽像 但並非真正的我
Some kind of abstraction, but there is no real me.
只是那麼一個意象... 非常模糊
Only an entity... something illusory.
並且儘管我可以掩藏冷酷
And though I can hide my cold gaze...
你與我握手仍感覺到我有血有肉
and you can shake my hand and feel flesh gripping yours...
而且你甚至會感到 我們的生活方式頗為相似
and may be you can even sense our life styles are probably comparable,
但我其實並非真我
I simply am not there.
" Ow "
" Mmm, yeah "
" I said, baby I just want you back "
" And I want you to stay "
早安
Good morning.
早安 漢密爾頓
Good morning, Hamilton. Nice tan.
" Whoa I'm walking on sunshine "
" Whoa "
來晚了 有氧操班有課 對不起 有人找嗎?
Late. Aerobics class. Sorry. Any messages ?
瑞斯基·哈里森的約會取消了 他沒說他取消的是什麼約會及其原因
Ricky Harrison has to cancel. He didn't say what he was cancelling or why.
我有時候會約瑞斯基在哈佛俱樂部打拳 還有呢?
I occasionally box with Ricky at the Harvard Club. Anyone else ?
- 斯賓塞約你在17號碼頭的福路戴斯喝酒 - 什麼時候?
- Spencer wants to meet for drinks at Fluties, Pier 17. - When ?
- 6點以後 我該怎麼答覆? - 不行 推掉
- After 6:00. And what should I say ? - Negative. Cancel it.
- 就說"不行" - 就說"不行"?
- Just say "no" - Just say "no" ?
好了 吉恩
Okay, Jean.
幫我在凱莫斯餐廳訂三個位 12點半
I need reservations for three at Camols at 12:30,
如果訂不到就換"蠟筆"餐廳
and if not there try Crayons.
- 好嗎? - 好的
- All right ? - Yes, sir.
哦 等等 我還要在阿卡迪亞 訂兩個位 星期四8點
Oh, wait. And I need reservations for two at Arcadia at 8:00 on Thursday.
浪漫晚餐?
Something romantic ?
不是
No.
挺傻的 當我沒說過 我自己來吧
Silly. Forget it. I'll make them.
- 不 我來訂 - 不 不
- No, I'll do it. - No, no.
- 聽話 給我拿杯礦泉水來 好嗎? - 你今天氣色不錯
- Be a doll and just get me a mineral water, okay ? - You look nice today.
別再穿這套衣服了
Don't wear that outfit again.
什麼? 我沒聽清
What ? I didn't hear you.
我說 你別再穿這套衣服了
I said, do not wear that outfit again.
- 穿套裝 裙子或者別的什麼 - 你不喜歡 但我穿的很襯
- Wear a dress, a skirt or something. - You don't like this, I take it.
得了 你打扮起來會更靚的
Come on. You're prettier than that.
- 謝了 帕特裏克 - 說我不在
- Thanks, Patrick. - I'm not here.
還有高跟鞋 我喜歡高跟的
And high heels. I like high heels.
"Feathered friends for 600."
"During courtship, the male frigate bird..."
"inflates to enormous size the red pouch found here."
" She's a craze you'd endorse She's a powerful force "
" You're obliged to conform when there's no other course "
" She used to look good to me but now I find her "
我還要成百上千朵玫瑰
" Simply irresistible " And I want hundreds of thousands of roses.
還有很多很多的巧克力糖
And lots of chocolate truffles,
在戈黛娃 再加上分半打開的牡蠣
Godiva, and oysters in the half shell.
我想好好聽聽羅伯特帕瑪新出的帶子
I'm trying to listen to the new Robert Palmer tape,
可伊芙琳 我所謂的未婚妻 在我耳邊嘮叨個不停
but Evelyn, my supposed fiancee, keeps buzzing in my ear.
安妮 蕾波維茲 我們要把安妮 蕾波維茲請來
Annie Leibovitz. We'll get Annie Leibovitz.
我們還得請個攝像師
And we'll have to get someone to videotape.
帕特裏克 我們必須這麼做
Patrick, we should do it.
- 做什麼? - 結婚 舉行婚宴
- Do what ? - Get married. Have a wedding.
不行 我工作太忙沒時間
No. I can't take the time off work.
你老爸差不多控制了整個公司 你想幹啥就能幹啥 傻瓜
Your father practically owns the company. You can do anything you like, silly.
- 我不想談這事 - 我反正也不喜歡這份差事
- I don't want to talk about it. - I hate that job anyway.
我不明白你幹嗎還在那兒幹
I don't see why you just don't quit.
因為我想和他們打成一片
Because I want to fit in.
" Simply irresistible "
威廉姆斯派對
Williams party.
我們到"空間"餐廳的時 候我都快哭了
I'm on the verge of tears by the time we arrive at Espace,
因為我幾乎肯定我們定不到好位子了
since I'm positive we won't have a decent table.
可是我們居然訂到了 這讓我長出了一口氣
But we do, and relief washes over me in an awesome wave.
帕特裏克 這是我侄女范登和她男朋友斯達什
Patrick, this is my cousin Vanden and her boyfriend Stash.
- 他們都是搞藝術的 - 菜單是用盲文寫的
- They're both artists. - The menu's in Braille.
- 我想你每個人都見過了 - 你美極了
- I see you've met everyone. - You look awful.
好的 好了
Okay. All right.
我差不多可以確定
I'm fairly certain that...
蒂莫西 布瑞斯和伊芙琳有私情
Timothy Bryce and Evelyn are having an affair.
蒂莫西是我認識的人裏面唯一一個有趣的人物
Timothy is the only interesting person I know.
我也根本不在乎伊芙琳知不知道
I'm almost completely indifferent as to whether Evelyn knows...
我和她最好的朋友庫特妮·羅林森也有私情
I'm having an affair with Courtney Rawlinson, her closest friend.
庫坦妮的相貌近乎完美
Courtney is almost perfect looking.
她通常都在用一或幾種迷幻藥
She's usually operating on one or more psychiatric drugs.
今晚我想是香奈克斯 嗯 哦
Tonight, I believe, it's Xanax. Mmm. Oh.
比她嗑藥更煩人的是
More disturbing than her drug use, though, is the fact that she's engaged...
她和路易斯 卡魯法 本行最大的蠢材定了婚
to Luis Carruthers, the biggest doofus in the business.
告訴我 斯達什
Tell me, Stash.
你覺得休南區是不是變得太...商業化了?
Do you think Soho is becoming too... commercial ?
- 是的 我感覺到了 - 哦 誰說的屁話
- Yes. I read that. - Oh, who gives a rat's ass ?
嘿 那會影響到我們的
Hey, that affects us.
好吧 那斯里蘭卡的大屠殺呢? 對我們也有影響嗎?
Well, what about the massacres in Sri Lanka, honey ? Doesn't that affect us too ?
你對斯里蘭卡瞭解多少?
Do you know anything about Sri Lanka ?
多少 比如說 錫克教徒在那裏 殺了成千上萬的以色列人
How, like, the Sikhs are killing tons of Israelis over there ?
得了 布瑞斯
Come on, Bryce.
比斯里蘭卡更嚴重的問題多得很呢
There are a lot more important problems than Sri Lanka to worry about.
- 比如? - 我們得廢除種族隔離制度 這是一樁
- Like what ? - Well, we have to end apartheid, for one,
減緩核軍備競賽 終結恐怖主義和世界饑荒
slow down the nuclear arms race, stop terrorism and world hunger.
我們要為無家可歸者提供食物和住所
We have to provide food and shelter for the homeless...
還有反對種族歧視和提高人權
and oppose racial discrimination and promote civil rights,
同時還要提高婦女平等權利
while also promoting equal rights for women.
我們要推動傳統道德價值
We have to encourage a return...
的回歸
to traditional moral values.
最重要的
Most importantly,
我們要提高全面社會責任感
we have to promote general social concern...
並且讓年輕人不再那麼唯利是圖
and less materialism in young people.
帕特裏克 多麼鼓舞人心的思想啊
Patrick, how thought provoking.
你好
Hello.
漂白? 你是要說"漂白"嗎?
Bleaching ? Are you trying to say "bleaching" ?
哦 上帝啊 有兩件事
Oh, my God. Two things.
第一: 切瑞蒂的東西不是想漂白就能漂白的 根本不可能
One: You can't bleach a Cerruti. Out of the question.
第二: 這床單只能在聖達菲才買得到
Two: I can only get these sheets in Santa Fe.
這些床單價值不菲 我一定要把它們洗乾淨
These are very expensive sheets, and I really need them cleaned.
太太 你要是再不閉上你的臭嘴 我就殺了你
Lady, if you don't shut your fucking mouth, I will kill you.
現在 聽好
Now, listen.
我再過20分鐘就要和羅納德 哈里森 在休伯特餐廳開個午餐會了
I have a lunch meeting at Hubert's in 20 minutes with Ronald Harrison.
我希望床單能在今天下午前洗乾淨
I need those sheets cleaned by this afternoon.
聽著 我聽不懂你的話! 真見鬼! 你這個笨蛋
Listen, I can't understand you ! This is crazy ! You're a fool.
我和你這種愚蠢的"娘們兒"沒法談!
I can't cope with this stupid "bitchee" !
- 懂了嗎? 天哪 - 帕特裏克?
- Understand ? Christ. - Patrick ?
嗨 帕特裏克
Hi, Patrick.
- 我猜就是你 - 你好 那個...
- I thought that was you. - Hello. This is...
不是很可笑嗎 大老遠跑來? 這確實是最好的洗衣店了
Isn't it ridiculous, coming all the way up here ? They really are the best.
那麼他們怎麼洗不掉這些污跡?
Then why can't they get these stains out ?
我是說 你能和他們談談嗎? 我跟他們一點說不通
I mean, can you talk to these people or something ? I'm not getting anywhere.
- 哦 這是什麼呀? - 唔 這是...
- Oh, what are those ? - Well, it's...
- 酸果蔓汁 - 真的嗎?
- Cranberry juice. Cranapple. - Really ?
聽著 如果你能幫我跟他們說說 我真的很感謝
Listen, if you could talk to them, I would really appreciate it.
太晚了 再過15分鐘我在休伯特餐廳有個約會
I'm really late. I have a lunch appointment at Hubert's in 15 minutes.
- 休伯特餐廳? 不是搬到市區了嗎? - 哦 天哪
- Hubert's ? That moved uptown, right ? - Oh, boy.
聽著 我得走了 謝謝你 維多利亞
Listen, I've gotta go. Thank you, Victoria.
也許下星期哪一天我們一起吃頓午飯
Maybe we could do lunch one day next week.
- 我常來市區的 星期六怎麼樣? - 我成天都在工作 恐怕不行
- I'm downtown quite often. What about a Saturday ? - I'm at work all the time.
- 下週六呢? - 沒問題
- Next Saturday ? Can't, - I'm afraid. Sure.
萊斯·密斯女子合唱隊日場表演見 聽著我真的必須走了
At a matinee of LesMis. Listen, I really gotta go.
- 哦 天哪 我會給你打電話的 - 好的 幹吧
- Oh, Christ. I'll call you. - Okay. Do.
聽著 你在和劉易斯約會 他從亞利桑那州來
Listen, you're dating Lewis, he's in Arizona.
你在耍我 我們根本沒有這種安排
You're fucking me, and we haven't made plans.
你今晚會吃什麼藥?
What could you possibly be up to tonight ?
- 別說了 我... - 吃一大把鋰劑?
- Stop it. I'm... - On a lot of lithium ?
在等路易斯的電話 他說今晚要給我打的
Waiting for Luis to call me. He said he'd call tonight.
蕩婦? 蕩婦 你在和一個混蛋約會
Pumpkin ? Pumpkin, you're dating an asshole.
- 嗯哼 - 蕩婦 你在和紐約最沒用的臭小子約會
- Mm-hmm. - Pumpkin, you're dating the biggest dickweed in New York.
蕩婦 你在和一個歪七倒八的臭小子約會
Pumpkin, you're dating a tumbling, tumbling dickweed.
帕特裏克 別再叫我蕩婦了 好嗎?
Patrick, stop calling me pumpkin, okay ?
- 我得掛了 - 考特妮?
- I have to go. - Courtney ?
- 嗯? - 去吃飯
- Hmm ? - Dinner.
- 不行 - 我說去朵西亞
- I can't. - I'm thinking Dorsia.
- 朵西亞還不錯 - 打扮得漂亮點
- Dorsia's nice. - Wear something fabulous.
哦 耶!
Oh, yeah!
這是朵西亞
Dorsia.
嗯 我知道有點晚了
Um, yes, I know it's a little late,
但還有可能訂到兩個8點到8點半的位子嗎?
but is it possible to reserve a table for two at 8:00 or 8:30, perhaps ?
在伊莉莎白雅頓做一下臉 真的很舒服
...a facial at Elizabeth Arden, which was really relaxing.
然後去波特瑞·巴恩
And then, to the Pottery Barn,
在那兒我買到了...
where I got this little...
- 這個小銀鬆餅盒 - 那是唐納德 特朗普的車嗎?
- silver muffin dish. - Is that Donald Trump's car ?
上帝啊 帕特裏克 別作聲
God, Patrick. Shut up.
你知道嗎 考特妮 你應該再吃點鋰劑 或者喝杯可樂
You know, Courtney, you should take some more lithium or have a Diet Coke.
咖啡因或許能幫你擺脫現在的疲塌
Some caffeine might get you out of this slump.
我只想要一個孩子
I just want a child.
兩個
Just two...
完美無暇的
perfect...
孩子
children.
- 我們到了嗎? - 是的
- Are we here ? - Yeah.
- 這兒是朵西亞嗎? - 是的 親愛的
- This is Dorsia ? - Yes, dear.
考特妮 你馬上就會嘗到花生醬湯
Courtney, you're gonna have the peanut butter soup...
熏鴨和南瓜泥
with smoked duck and mashed squash.
紐約午場把這個叫 "好玩又神秘的小菜"
New York Matinee called it "a playful but mysterious little dish."
你會喜歡的 接下來是紫羅蘭和松子襯底的紅鯛魚
You'll love it. And then the red snapper with violets and pine nuts.
我想這樣的搭配很合適
I think that'll follow nicely.
謝謝 帕特裏克
Mmm. Thanks, Patrick.
帕特裏克 多謝你照看考特妮
Patrick, thanks so much for looking after Courtney.
朵西亞 真讓人難忘
Dorsia. How impressive.
你到底怎麼在這兒訂到位的?
How on Earth did you get a reservation there ?
運氣吧 我想
Lucky, I guess.
這西裝棒極了
That's a wonderful suit.
別告訴我 別講 讓我猜
Don't tell me. Don't tell me. Let me guess.
唔 是華倫天奴嗎?
Mmm, Valentino Couture ?
- 嗯哼 - 唔
- Uh-huh. - Hmm.
- 看起來料子真軟 - 君子動口不動手 路易斯
- It looks so soft. - Your compliment was sufficient, Luis.
你好 海博斯坦姆 好炫的領帶 你還好嗎?
Hello, Halberstram. Nice tie. How the hell are you ?
艾倫把我誤認成那個蠢貨馬克斯 海博斯坦姆了
Allen has mistaken me for this dickhead, Marcus Halberstram.
因為馬克斯也在P&P工作 這倒也合理
It seems logical because Marcus also works at P&P,
而且他幹的活和我一模一樣
and in fact does the same exact thing I do.
他也愛穿華倫天奴西服 戴奧利弗人眼鏡
He also has a penchant for Valentino suits and Oliver Peoples glasses.
馬克斯和我去的理髮店都是一家
Marcus and I even go to the same barber,
而我的髮型比他稍微好那麼一點
although I have a slightly better haircut.
- 蘭塞姆那單生意怎麼樣了? - 嗯 一切正常
- How's the Ransom account going, Marcus ? - It's, uh, all right.
是嗎? 有趣 你沒說好極了
Really ? That's interesting. It's not, uh, not great.
- 哦 嗯 你知道的 - 那麼 塞西莉亞呢?
- Oh, well, you know. - So, how's Cecilia ?
- 她是個好姑娘 - 哦 沒錯 我很幸運
- She's a great girl. - Oh, yeah. I'm very lucky.
- 嗯 - 嘿 艾倫 恭喜你在做費希爾那單生意
- Mm-hmm. - Hey, Allen, congratulations on the Fisher account.
- 謝謝 百特 - 聽著 我叫保羅 笨蛋
- Thank you, Baxter. - Listen, Paul. Squash.
給我打電話 星期五怎麼樣?
Call me. How about Friday ?
不行啊 我8點半在朵西亞訂了位
No can do. I got an 8:30 res at Dorsia.
美味的海膽酸橘汁醃魚
Great sea urchin ceviche.
朵西亞星期五的位子? 他怎麼搶到的?
Dorsia on Friday night ? How'd he swing that ?
我想他在吹牛
I think he's lying.
- 什麼東西? - 新名片
- Is that a gram ? - New card.
你們看怎麼樣?
What do you think ?
哇霍 棒極了
Whoa-ho. Very nice.
- 瞧瞧 - 昨天才印出來的
- Look at that. - Picked them up from the printer's yesterday.
- 配色不錯 - 這是關鍵
- Good coloring. - That's bone.
用了一種叫司麗安-瑞爾的字體
And the lettering is something called Silian Rail.
很酷 巴特曼 但算不了啥 看這個
It's very cool, Bateman, but that's nothing. Look at this.
真是太棒了
That is really nice.
淡褐色 羅馬裏亞字體 你看怎麼樣?
Eggshell with Romalian type. What do you think ?
很好
Nice.
天哪 真是蓋了 你這種傻瓜蛋怎麼變得這麼有品位了?
Jesus. That is really super. How a nitwit like you get so tasteful?
我不敢相信布瑞斯...
I can't believe that Bryce...
居然認為范·派頓的名片比我的好
prefers Van Patten's card to mine.
但是別急 你們還沒看到好的呢
But wait. You ain't seen nothin' yet.
瑞斯德字體 淡色光暈... 白底
Raised lettering, pale nimbus... white.
令人難忘 太好了
Impressive. Very nice.
嗯
Hmm.
讓我們見識一下保羅·艾倫的名片
Let's see Paul Allen's card.
看看那精巧的白色配色
Look at that subtle off-white coloring.
品位十足的內蘊
The tasteful thickness of it.
哦 上帝啊 它還帶了水印
Oh, my God. It even has a watermark.
有什麼不妥嗎 帕特裏克?
Is something wrong, Patrick ?
你出了好多汗
You're sweating.
你好 我是帕特·巴特曼
Hello. Pat Bateman.
你要...嗯...錢嗎?
You want some, uh, money ?
還有食物?
Some food ?
- 你要的是這些嗎? - 我...我餓壞了
- Is this what you need ? - I'm-I'm hungry.
是啊 還凍壞了 是不是?
Yeah. Cold out too, isn't it ?
幹嗎不找份活幹? 你這麼餓 幹嗎不找份活幹?
Why don't you get a job ? If you're so hungry, why don't you get a job ?
我失業了
I lost my job.
為什麼? 你酗酒嗎?
Why ? You drinking ?
你就是為此丟了飯碗的嗎? 還是做了什麼內部交易?
Is that why you lost it ? Insider trading ?
開玩笑而已
Just joking.
- 聽著 你叫什麼? - 阿爾
- Listen, what's your name ? - Al.
- 嗯? 說響點 快點 - 阿爾
- Hmm ? Speak up. Come on. - Al.
去找份活幹 阿爾
Get a goddamn job, Al.
你消極處事 就是這個拖了你的後腿
You got a negative attitude. That's what's stopping you.
你必須努力振作 我會幫你的
You gotta get your act together. I'll help you.
你真好 先生 你是個...是個好人
You are so kind, mister. You're a kind... You're a kind man.
- 沒什麼的 - 我看得出來
- It's okay. - I can tell.
求求你 你要告訴我該怎麼做 你得幫幫我
Please, you gotta tell me what to do. You gotta help me.
我凍壞了 也餓極了
I'm so cold, I'm hungry.
你知道你有多臭嗎?
You know how bad you smell ?
你像堆臭狗屎 你知道嗎?
You reek of shit. Do you know that ?
真抱歉 是因為...
I'm sorry. It's just that...
我也不知道
I don't know.
我和你根本不是一路人
I don't have anything in common with you.
哦 哦 謝謝你 先生 謝謝你
Oh. Oh, thank you, mister. Thank you.
我凍懷了
I'm cold out here.
- 你知道你是怎麼樣的一個窩囊廢嗎? - 什麼?
- You know what a fucking loser you are ? - What ?
你的皮膚真好 巴特曼先生
What beautiful skin you have, Mr. Bateman.
那麼細膩 光滑
So fine, so smooth.
我具有人類的一切特徵...
I have all the characteristics of a human being...
髮膚血肉
flesh, blood, skin, hair...
但沒有一個清晰可辨的表情
but not a single, clear, identifiable emotion,
除了貪婪和厭惡
except for greed and disgust.
我內心深處發生了可怕的變化
Something horrible is happening inside of me,
但我不知道為什麼
and I don't know why.
我屬於黑夜的嗜血惡性蔓延到了白晝
My nightly bloodlust has overflowed into my days.
我感到了垂死的氣息 處於狂怒的邊緣
I feel lethal, on the verge of frenzy.
我想我理智的面具就快跌落了
I think my mask of sanity is about to slip.
" Deck the halls with boughs of holly "
" Fa la la la la La la la la "
" 'Tis the season to be jolly "
嘿 麥克洛伊 是說什麼?
Hey, Mc Cloy, what do you say ?
嘿 漢密爾頓 聖誕快樂
Hey, Hamilton. Have a holly, jolly Christmas.
- 艾倫還在接收費希爾那單生意嗎? - 當然 還能有誰?
- Is Allen still handling the Fisher account ? - Of course. Who else ?
- 聖誕問候 - 聖誕快樂 帕特裏克
- Mistletoe alert. - Merry Xmas, Patrick.
- 聖誕快樂 哈里 - 聖誕快樂
- Merry Xmas, Harry. - Merry Christmas.
- 你來晚了 親愛的 是的 你晚了 - 我沒來晚
- You're late, honey. Oh, yes, you are. - I'm not late.
我一直在這兒 你沒看到我罷了
I've been here the entire time. You just didn't see me.
跟雪球說聲好 雪球說"聖誕快樂 帕特裏克"
Say hello to Snowball. Snowball says, "Merry Christmas, Patrick."
- 什麼呀? - 一隻可愛的小豬豬 不是嗎?
- What is it ? - It's a little baby piggly-wiggly, isn't it ?
是只越南大肚子豬
It's a Vietnamese potbellied pig.
真是可愛的寵物 不是嗎?
They make darling pets. Don't you ?
不是嗎?
Don't you ?
別悶悶不樂的 帕特裏克 你簡直就和聖誕怪傑一樣了
Stop scowling, Patrick. You're such a grinch.
那麼聖誕怪傑先生有何聖誕心願?
And what does Mr. Grinch want for Christmas ?
別再提隆胸的事了
And don't say breast implants again.
- 艾倫 - 馬克斯 聖誕快樂
- Allen. - Marcus. Merry Christmas.
- 你怎麼樣? 埋頭工作嗎? - 好久不見了
- How you been ? Workaholic, I suppose ? - Haven't seen you in a while.
嘿 漢密爾頓 我們要去尼爾餐廳了 車子在前面等著呢
Hey, Hamilton. We're goin' to Nell's. Limo's out front.
- 我們應該一起吃頓飯 - 也許你能帶上...
- We should have dinner. - Maybe you could bring...
- 塞西莉亞? - 對 塞西莉亞
- Cecilia ? - Yes, Cecilia.
哦 塞西莉亞會求之不得的
Oh, Cecilia would adore it.
那麼好 就這麼定了 馬克斯
Well, then, let's do it, Marcus.
- 很好的派對 - 謝謝
- Great party. - Thanks.
帕特裏克 他怎麼叫你馬克斯呢?
Patrick, why is he calling you Marcus ?
聖誕問候
Mistletoe alert.
馬克斯 海博斯坦姆定的兩個7點的位
Marcus Halberstram for two at 7:00.
不 我想知道 行不行? 我就是為這裏的芫荽龍蝦湯來的
No, l want to know, okay ? I came here for the cilantro crawfish gumbo,
這也是我們來這家餐廳的唯一理由
which is, after all, the only excuse one could have for being in this restaurant,
可是這現在卻空空如也
which is, by the way, almost completely empty.
- 非常抱歉 先生 - J&B不摻水 再來杯珂羅娜啤酒
- I'm very sorry, sir. - J&B straight, and a Corona.
- 要聽聽... - 雙份純馬提尼酒
- Would you like to hear... - Double Absolute martini.
好的 先生 要聽聽今晚的特色菜嗎?
Yes, sir. Would you like to hear the specials ?
不想惹火的話就免了吧
Not if you want to keep your spleen.
人們蜂擁而至 這裏真夠熱鬧的
This is a real beehive of activity, Halberstram. This place is hot.
- 非常熱鬧 - 聽著 這裏的混湯和炭燒芝麻菜
- Very hot. - Listen, the mud soup and charcoal arugula...
真實非同凡響
are outrageous here.
- 是嗎 好吧 你來晚了 - 嘿 我身不由己
- Yeah, well, you're late. - Hey, I'm a child of divorce.
饒了我吧
Give me a break.
- 我想他們把豬裏脊換成果子凍了 - 我們應該去朵西亞的
- I see they've omitted the pork loin with lime Jell-O. - We should've gone to Dorsia.
- 我應該在那兒訂個位的 - 沒人再去那兒了
- I could've gotten us a table. - Nobody goes there anymore.
那是伊萬娜 特朗普嗎?
Is that Ivana Trump ?
哦 天 帕特裏克 我是說 馬克斯 你在想什麼?
Oh, geez, Patrick. I mean, Marcus. What are you thinking ?
伊萬娜怎麼會在特克薩卡納出現?
Why would Ivana be at Texarkana ?
那麼 嗯 原來不是羅斯查爾德在做費希爾那單生意嗎?
So, uh, wasn't Rothchild originally handling the Fisher account ?
- 你怎麼弄到收的? - 這我可以告訴你 海博斯坦姆
- How'd you get it ? - Well, I could tell you that, Halberstram,
但隨後我就要殺你滅口
but then I'd have to kill you.
我喜歡肢解少女 你不知道我已經極度瘋狂了嗎?
I like to dissect girls. Did you know I'm utterly insane ?
你膚色真不錯 我是說非常引人注目
Great tan, Marcus. I mean, really impressive.
- 在哪兒曬的? - 沙龍裏
- Where do you tan ? - Salon.
我家裏有張曬床 你應該過來看看
I've got a tanning bed at home. You should look into it.
還有 嗯 塞西莉亞
And, uh, Cecilia.
她怎麼樣了? 他今晚在哪兒?
How is she ? Where is she tonight ?
塞西莉亞在 嗯... 你也知道她這個人啦
Cecilia, uh... Well, you know Cecilia.
我想她在和 嗯 伊芙琳 威廉姆斯共進晚餐呢
I think she's having dinner with, um, Evelyn Williams.
伊芙琳? 超級美臀
Evelyn ? Great ass.
和那個窩囊廢帕特裏克·巴特曼 混在一起 真可惜
Goes out with that loser Patrick Bateman. What a dork.
再來杯馬提尼 保羅?
Another martini, Paul ?
你喜歡休伊 劉易斯 & the News的歌嗎?
You like Huey Lewis and the News ?
嗯 還好啦
Um, they're okay.
他們的早期作品對我而言太前衛了些
They're early work was a little too new wave for my taste.
但83年《運動》專集出來的時候
But when Sports came out in '83,
我想他們真正找到了自我 無論在市場上還是藝術上
I think they really came into their own, commercially and artistically.
整張專集聲音明朗乾脆
The whole album has a clear, crisp sound,
趨於完美的專業演繹煥發出的嶄新光輝
and a new sheen of consummate professionalism...
著實為這些單曲增色不少
that really gives the songs a big boost.
他已經和埃爾維斯 科斯特洛相提並論
He's been compared to Elvis Costello,
但我以為休伊具有更為良好的 憤世嫉俗的的幽默感
but I think Huey has a far more bitter, cynical sense of humor.
- 喂 海博斯坦姆? - 什麼事 艾倫?
- Hey, Halberstram ? - Yes, Allen ?
為什麼到處都是流行服飾的專欄?
Why are there copies of the Style section all over the place ?
你有...你有養狗嗎? 有狗糧之類的東西嗎?
Do you... Do you have a dog ? A little chow or something ?
- 沒有 艾倫 - 那是雨衣嗎?
- No, Allen. - Is that a raincoat ?
是的 沒錯
Yes, it is.
87年 休伊推出了
In '87, Huey released this...
《前端》 他的最佳專集
Fore, their most accomplished album.
我認為最佳單曲毫無疑問應歸於《殺人單曲》
I think their undisputed masterpiece is "Hip To Be Square."
這首歌如此吸引人 以至大多數人可能都不會去聽歌詞
The song's so catchy, most people probably don't listen to the lyrics.
但歌詞是值得回味的 因為它不光是說
But they should, because it's not just about...
迎合時尚之快樂 以及流行潮流之重要
the pleasures of conformity and the importance of trends.
它也是樂隊的個人宣言... 嘿 保羅!
It's also a personal statement about the band itself. Hey, Paul !
" You couldn't take the punishment "
現在去朵西亞定位呀
Try getting a reservation at Dorsia now,
你這個蠢貨!
you fuckin' stupid bastard !
他媽的混蛋!
You fucking bastard !
" You might think I'm crazy but I don't even care "
" 'Criverse I can tell what's going on "
" It's hip to be square "
" like my bands in mini-suits "
" I watch them on TV "
" I'm working out most everyday "
" And watching what I eat "
" They tell me that it's good for me "
" But I don't even care "
" I know that it's crazy I know that it's nowhere "
" But there is no denying that "
" It's hip to be square "
他全身赤裸站在桌子上
He was completely naked and standing up on the table.
什麼都沒穿 並且...
He had no clothes on what so ever, and he...
帕特裏克? 帕特裏克
Patrick ? Patrick.
是你嗎?
Is that you ?
不 路易斯 不是我 你搞錯了
No, Luis, it's not me. You're mistaken.
這是我最好的朋友 帕特裏克·巴特曼
This is my very good friend, Patrick Bateman.
你去哪兒? 我們要去尼爾餐廳 格溫多林的父親要把它買下來
Where are you going ? We're going to Nell's. Gwendolyn's father is buying it.
噢
Ooh.
你從哪兒搞來的這睡袋?
Where did you get that overnight bag ?
在吉恩-保羅-高提耶買的
Jean-Paul Gaultier.
我到了保羅·艾倫的家
When I get to Paul Allen's place,
用他口袋的的鑰匙開的門
I use the keys I took from his pocket...
在處置屍體之前
before disposing of the body.
我著實驚慌了一陣
There is a moment of sheer panic...
當我看到保羅的公寓對面就是公園
when I realize that Paul's apartment overlooks the park...
顯然房價要比我的高得多
and is obviously more expensive than mine.
我讓自己平靜下來 進入他的臥室
I calm myself and move into the bedroom,
找到了他的皮箱並開始裝行李
where I find his suitcase and start to pack.
保羅該去做個短途旅行了
It's time for Paul to take a little trip.
我該把這混蛋送到哪兒去呢?
Where do I send the bastard ?
達拉斯?
Dallas ?
巴黎? 新加坡?
Paris ? Singapore ?
倫敦? 我要把這混蛋送到倫敦去
London ? I'll send the asshole to London.
嗨 我是保羅
Hi. This is Paul.
我被派到倫敦出幾天差
I've been called away to London for a few days.
梅瑞狄斯 我回來就給你打電話 回頭見 寶貝
Meredith, I'll call you when I get back. Hasta la vista, baby.
" Lady in red "
" ls dancing with me "
" Cheek to cheek "
" There's nobody here "
什麼事?
What is it ?
- 帕特裏克 - 什麼 吉恩?
- Patrick. - Yes, Jean ?
- 有位唐納德 金葆先生要見你 - 誰?
- There's a Mr. Donald Kimball here to see you. - Who ?
唐納德 金葆探長
Detective Donald Kimball.
告訴他我去吃午餐了
Tell him I'm at lunch.
帕特裏克 現在才10點半 我想他知道你在這兒
Patrick, it's only 10:30. I think he knows you're here.
那麼就讓他進來吧
Send him in, I guess.
聽著 約翰 你該穿合你體型的衣服
Now, John, you've gotta wear clothes in proportion to your physique.
朋友 穿粗條紋的襯衫是有講究的
There are definite do's and don'ts, good buddy, of wearing a bold-striped shirt.
它必須配深色的
A bold-striped shirt calls for solid-colored...
或者圖案鮮明的西裝和領帶
or discreetly patterned suits and ties.
對 給設計師百分之十五小費就行
Yes, always tip the stylist 15 percent.
聽著 約翰 我得掛了 T·布恩·皮肯斯來了
Listen, John, I've gotta go. T. Boone Pickens just walked in.
開個玩笑 不 不用給沙龍老闆小費
Just joking. No, don't tip the owner of the salon.
好了嗎 約翰 好的
Okay, John ? Right.
知道了 抱歉了
Got it. Sorry about that.
不 該抱歉的是我 我該先預約的
No, I'm sorry. I should've made an appointment.
是很重要的事嗎?
Was that anything important ?
哦 沒什麼 談談生意
Oh, that ? Just mulling over business problems,
找找機會 飛短流長 閒聊瞎扯而已
examining opportunities, exchanging rumors, spreading gossip.
你好
Hi.
- 我是唐納德 金葆 - 你好 帕特·巴特曼
- I'm Donald Kimball. - Hi. Pat Bateman.
- 幸會 - 抱歉就這麼闖進來了
- Nice to meet you. - Sorry to barge in on you like this.
我知道幹你們這行的有多忙
I know how busy you guys can get.
那麼 呃 我們要談點什麼呢?
So, what's the, uh, topic of discussion ?
梅瑞狄斯 鮑威爾雇了我
I've been hired by Meredith Powell...
調查保羅·艾倫失蹤的事
to investigate the disappearance of Paul Allen.
明白了 嗯 保羅失蹤的事 嗯
I see, yeah. Paul's disappearance, yeah.
這不算正式的問話
So it's nothing that official.
- 我只是問幾個關於保羅·艾倫和你本人的問題 - 要咖啡嗎?
- I just have some questions about Paul Allen and yourself. - Coffee ?
- 不 不必了 - 礦泉水?
- No, I'm okay. - Apollinaris ?
不 真的不必
No, I'm okay.
能為...
Can you bring Mr....
- 金葆 不必麻煩了 - 金葆先生拿瓶礦泉水進來嗎?
- Kimball. No, I'm okay. - Mr. Kimball a bottle of Apollinaris.
小意思
It's no problem.
那麼我們要談什麼來著?
So, what's the topic of discussion ?
保羅·艾倫失蹤的事
The disappearance of Paul Allen.
呃嗯 對 唔 我還沒...
Uh-huh, right. Well, I, um, haven't...
沒聽說任何關於他失蹤的事呢
I haven't heard anything about the disappearance or anything.
只是沒在報紙第六版上看到
Not on page six, at least.
- 我想他的家人還不想聲張 - 懂了 要檸檬汁嗎?
- I think his family wants this kept quiet. - Understandable. Lime ?
- 不用了 真的 - 真的不要 我隨時都可以為你拿一杯來的
- No, really, I'm okay. - You sure ? I can always get you a lime.
就問幾個簡單的問題 我存檔用的 好嗎?
Just some preliminary questions that I need for my own files, okay ?
問吧
Shoot.
- 你的年齡? - 27歲
- Hold old are you ? - Twenty-seven.
- 在哪兒上的學? - 哈佛
- Where did you go to school ? - Harvard.
- 然後上了哈佛商學院 - 住址?
- Then Harvard Business School. - Your address ?
美國花園大廈 西81街
The American Gardens Building, West 81st Street.
- 好極了 很好 - 謝謝
- Nice. Very nice. - Thanks.
- 你能告訴我什麼有關保羅·艾倫的事? - 我有點摸不著頭腦
- What can you tell me about Paul Allen ? - I'm at a loss.
- 他就是耶魯那幫人的一分子 - 耶魯那幫人?
- He was part of that whole Yale thing. - "Yale thing" ?
- 對 耶魯那幫人 - 你指的是什麼?
- Yeah, Yale thing. - What do you mean, "Yale thing" ?
唔 大致就是說那些私底下搞同性戀
Well, I think for one that he was probably a closet homosexual...
還大吸可卡因的傢伙
who did a lot of cocaine.
這就是耶魯那幫人
That "Yale thing."
除了你剛才說的 他還是什麼樣的人呢?
What kind of man was he, besides the information you've just given ?
- 這裏沒什麼相互對質的事吧? - 你覺得像嗎?
- I hope I'm not being cross-examined here. - You feel like that ?
不 我沒那個意思
No, not really.
保羅常去什麼地方?
Where did Paul hang out ?
- 常去的地方? - 你知道的
- Hang out ? - Yeah, you know, hang out.
讓我想想 嗯 在新港 哈里餐廳
Let me think. Um, the Newport, Harry's,
福路戴斯 印度支那
Fluties, Indochina,
尼爾餐廳 康乃爾俱樂部
Nell's, the Cornell Club,
- 紐約遊艇俱樂部 - 他有遊艇嗎?
- the New York Yacht Club. - He had a yacht ?
- 不 他不過常去那兒 - 他在哪兒上的學?
- No, he just hung out there. - And where did he go to school ?
你還不知道嗎?
Don't you know this ?
我只是想知道你是否知道
I just wanted to know if you know.
在進耶魯前 如果我沒記錯 是在聖保羅學校
Before Yale, if I remember correctly, St. Paul's.
聽著 我只是... 只想幫幫忙
Listen, I just... I just wanna help.
我明白
I understand.
你們有目擊證人或者指紋嗎?
Do you have any witnesses or fingerprints ?
哦 他的留言機上留話說他去倫敦了
Well, there's a message on his answering machine that says he went to London.
- 那麼可能他確實去倫敦了 是不是? - 他的女朋友不相信
- Well, maybe he did, huh ? - His girlfriend doesn't think so.
- 有人在倫敦見過他嗎? - 實際上 有
- But has anyone seen him in London ? - Actually, yes.
但我很難確證
Hmm. But I've had a hard time getting actual verification.
一位叫斯蒂芬·休斯的說他在倫敦的餐廳見到過他
A Stephen Hughes said he saw him at a restaurant there.
但我去查了 結果是
But I checked it out, and what happened is...
他把一位叫赫伯特·安斯沃思的人認作保羅了 所以...
he mistook a Herbert Ainsworth for Paul, so...
- 他的公寓遭竊了嗎? - 沒有
- Had his apartment been burglarized ? - No, actually, it hadn't.
就不見了一些化妝品 一套西裝 和一些行李
Toiletries were missing, a suit was gone, so was some luggage. That's it.
我是說 還沒人在做刑事調查 是吧?
I mean, no one's dealing with the homicide squad yet or anything, right ?
不 還沒有 正如我說過的 我們還不確定
No, not yet. As I said, we're not sure.
基本上還沒有看到或聽到什麼
Basically, no one's seen or heard anything.
- 很典型 不是嗎? - 只是很奇怪
- So typical, isn't it ? - It's just strange.
某一天 某個身邊的人
One day, someone's walking around,
上得好好的班 生龍活虎的 然而...
going to work, alive, and then...
什麼都沒了
Nothing.
突然他消失得無影無蹤了
People just disappear.
大地...突然裂開把他吞進去了
The earth just... opens up and swallows them.
古怪 確實古怪
Eerie. Really eerie.
聽著 我得失陪了
Listen, you'll have to excuse me.
再過20分鐘 我和克裏斯·哈克斯泰堡在四季餐廳有個午餐會
I have a lunch meeting with Cliff Huxtable at Four Seasons in 20 minutes.
四季餐廳? 從新市區去不是很遠嗎?
The Four Seasons ? Isn't that a little far uptown ?
- 我的意思是 你可能要遲到了 - 不 這裏附近就有一家
- I mean, aren't you gonna be late ? - No, there's one down here.
- 哦 真的嗎? 我還不知道呢 - 不錯 很好的餐廳
- Oh, really ? I didn't know that. - Yeah, it's very good.
聽著 如果你想起了什麼 任何事...
Listen, if anything else occurs to you, any information...
- 沒問題 我會一五一十全告訴你的 - 太好了
- Absolutely. I'm 100 percent with you. - Great.
耽誤你的時間了 巴特曼先生
And thanks for your time, Mr. Bateman.
- 再會 - 再見
- Bye-bye. - Good-bye.
- 我以前沒見過你 - 你沒注意看而已
- I haven't seen you around here. - You just haven't been lookin'.
- 想到我的公寓看看嗎? - 我一般不去的
- Would you like to see my apartment ? - I'm not supposed to.
你到底來不來?
Do you wanna come to my apartment or not ?
我一般不去 但也有例外
I'm not supposed to, but I can make an exception.
你收信用卡嗎?
Do you take a credit card ?
開個玩笑
I'm joking.
來吧 上車
Come on. Get in.
我要一個二十幾歲的姑娘
I'd like a girl. Early 20s.
金髮的 會玩雙人的 雙人
Blonde, who does couples. Couples.
我沒法把金髮更為強調 金髮女郎
And I really can't stress blonde enough. Blonde.
我叫保羅
I'm Paul.
我叫保羅·艾倫 你聽明白了嗎?
My name's Paul Allen. You got that ?
你叫克利斯蒂 叫你克利斯蒂你才應
You're Christie. You're to respond only to Christie.
明白了嗎?
Is that clear ?
" If you don't know me by now "
" If you don't know me "
" You will never never know me "
你在喝的是很棒的夏敦埃酒
That's a very fine chardonnay you're drinking.
我要你把你那兒洗洗乾淨
I want you to clean your vagina.
" If you don't know me by now "
" You will never never know me "
不 從後面來 跪下去
No. From behind. Get on your knees.
你的身體很美
You have a very nice body.
嗯?
Mm-hmm ?
謝謝 讓她上來
Thank you. Send her up.
克利斯蒂 出來擦乾身體
Christie, get out and dry off.
選件浴袍...不要穿睡衣...
Choose a robe... not the Bijan...
再來客廳見我和我們的客人 喝一杯
and come and meet me and our guest in the living room for drinks.
你來了 真可愛
You've arrived. How lovely.
把大衣給我吧
Let me take your coat.
我叫保羅 你能來真是太好了
I'm Paul. How good of you to come.
頭髮還不夠金黃 不是嗎?
Not quite blonde, are you ?
顏色有點暗
More dirty blonde.
我要叫你薩比裏娜
I'm gonna call you Sabrina.
我叫保羅·艾倫
I'm Paul Allen.
那麼
So.
你們不想知道我幹哪行的嗎?
Don't you wanna know what I do ?
- 不 - 不用了
- No. - No, not really.
唔 我在華爾街上班
Well, I work on Wall Street...
P&P公司
for Pierce & Pierce.
你們聽說過嗎?
Have you heard of it ?
你的家真不錯 保羅
You have a really nice place here, Paul.
房租多少?
How much did you pay for it ?
唔 實際上
Well, actually,
這不干你事 克利斯蒂
that's none of your business, Christie.
但我可以明確地告訴你 房租當然不會便宜
But I can assure you, it certainly wasn't cheap.
不 別吸煙 這兒禁止吸煙
No. No smoking. Not in here.
瓦爾達松露?
Varda truffle ?
我不想讓你們喝醉
I don't want you to get drunk,
但那兒有很好的夏敦埃酒 你卻不喝
but that's a very fine chardonnay you're not drinking.
喜歡菲爾·柯林斯嗎?
Do you like Phil Collins ?
自從1980年創世紀發行了專輯《公爵》之後
I've been a big Genesis fan ever since the release...
我就成了他們的大樂迷
of their 1980 album Duke.
在此之前 我對他們的作品一竅不通
Before that, I really didn't understand any of their work.
它們太藝術了 太費解了
It was too artsy, too intellectual.
正是在《公爵》裏
It was on Duke where...
菲爾·柯林斯脫穎而出
Phil Collins' presence became more apparent.
我認為《無形的接觸》是創世紀 無可爭議的最佳單曲
I think Invisible Touch is the group's undisputed masterpiece.
它是有關不可捉摸事務的史詩性沉思
It's an epic meditation on intangibility.
同時 它又深化豐富了
At the same time, it deepens and enriches...
緊接著三張專集的內涵
the meaning of the preceding three albums.
克利斯蒂 把浴袍脫掉
Christie, take off the robe.
請聽班克斯·柯林斯和盧瑟福的
Listen to the brilliant ensemble playing...
輝煌的合唱
of Banks, Collins and Rutherford.
你甚至能聽辨出每件樂器的細微差別
You can practically hear every nuance of every instrument.
薩比裏娜 把衣服脫掉
Sabrina, remove your dress.
談到作詞和作曲
In terms of lyrical craftsmanship and sheer songwriting,
這張專集攀上了一個新的高峰
this album hits a new peak of professionalism.
薩比裏娜 你為什麼不 嗯 跳跳舞呢
Sabrina, why don't you, uh, dance a little.
舉《混亂之島》的歌詞為例
Take the lyrics to "Land of Confusion."
在這首歌裏 菲爾·柯林斯
In this song, Phil Collins...
談到了政府濫用權力的問題
addresses the problems of abusive political authority.
《陷得太深》是80年代最感人的流行歌曲
"In Too Deep" is the most moving pop song of the 1980s...
有關夫妻之間的彼此忠貞
about monogamy and commitment.
這歌如此積極向上
The song is extremely uplifting.
歌詞積極樂觀
Their lyrics are as positive and affirmative...
象 呃 任何我所聽到的搖滾樂一樣
as, uh, anything I've heard in rock.
克利斯蒂 跪下來
Christie, get down on your knees...
把屁股對著薩比裏娜
so Sabrina can see your asshole.
菲爾·柯林斯的獨唱生涯
Phil Collins' solo career...
似乎商業味更濃
seems to be more commercial,
因此狹義地說更讓人滿意
and therefore more satisfying in a narrower way,
特別是像《今夜浮空》 和《針對可能》這樣的歌
especially songs like "In the Air Tonight" and "Against All Odds."
薩比裏娜 別光看呀 用舔的
Sabrina, don't just stare at it. Eat it.
我還認為菲爾·柯林斯在樂隊的表現
I also think that Phil Collins works best...
比他獨唱要好
within the confines of the group than as a solo artist.
我強調的是作為一個藝術家
And I stress the word "artist."
這首是《薩斯賽迪歐》
This is "Sussudio."
一首非常非常好的歌 我個人的最愛
A great, great song. A personal favorite.
看著鏡頭
Look at the camera.
" All the time "
" Su-Sussuido "
" Oh, oh "
" Now, she don't even know my name "
" But I think she likes mejust the same "
" Su- Sussuido "
" Oh, oh "
" Oh, if she'd call me I'd be there "
" I'd come running "
克利斯蒂 看著鏡頭
Christie, look at the camera.
" All of my life "
" I feel so good "
" If I just say the worrd "
" Su-Sussuido "
別碰表
Don't touch the watch.
我們能走了嗎?
Can we go now ?
還沒完呢
We're not through yet.
如果她們性情很好而相貌平平 還有誰會去理她們
If they have a good personality and they are not great looking, then who fucking cares ?
我們只是打個比方 好嗎?
Let's just say hypothetically, okay ?
如果她們性情好會怎麼樣?
What if they have a good personality ?
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
根本沒有性情好的女人
There are no girls with good personalities.
所謂性情好包括要有一個強壯的身體
A good personality consists of a chick with a little hard body...
可以滿足各種各樣的性需要
who will satisfy all sexual demands...
但不能過分淫蕩
without being too slutty about things...
並且還要守口如瓶
and who will essentially keep her dumb fucking mouth shut.
擁有良好性情的女人
The only girls with good personalities...
也許很聰明 也許很有趣 也許蠢得要死 或者智力超群...
who are smart or maybe funny or halfway intelligent or talented...
只要上帝才知道這是什麼意思... 都是醜女人
though God knows what the fuck that means... are ugly chicks.
毫無疑問 因為這是她們彌補
Absolutely. And this is because they have to make up...
她們缺乏吸引力的唯一方法
for how fucking unattractive they are.
- 你們知道埃德·蓋因怎麼談女人的嗎? - 坎奈爾酒吧的領班?
- Do you know what Ed Gein said about women ? - Maitre d' at Canal Bar ?
- 不 50年代的連環殺手 威斯康星州的 - 他怎麼說的?
- No, serial killer, Wisconsin, in the 50s. - And what did Ed say ?
"我在街上看到漂亮娘們的時候 我會想兩件事"
"When I see a pretty girl walking down the street, I think two things.
"一方面我想和她約會與她聊天
"One part of me wants to take her out and talk to her,
對她照顧備至 小心呵護"
be real nice and sweet and treat her right."
那麼他另一方面想幹嗎?
And what did the other part of him think ?
"把她腦袋插在木棍上會怎麼樣? "
What her head would look like on a stick.
嗨 我想聽聽你們的意見
Hi, guys. I wanna get your opinion on something.
這是我的名片
It's my business card.
我也決定做張新的了
I decided to get a new one too.
哦 它...
Oh, it's...
相對不錯 路易斯
Very nice, Luis.
謝謝
Thank you.
聽著 晚飯去哪兒吃?
Listen, what about dinner ?
你就會說這個嗎? 范·派頓 "晚飯去他媽的哪兒吃? "
Is that all you ever have to contribute, Van Patten ? "What about fucking dinner" ?
開心點 巴特曼 你怎麼了? 早上沒做指壓按摩嗎?
Cheer up there, Bateman. What's the matter ? No shiatsu this morning ?
- 再碰我 我就跟你沒完 - 別激動 夥計
- Keep touching me like that, you'll draw back a stump. - Hold on there, little buddy.
失陪了
Excuse me.
上帝啊 帕特裏克 幹嗎在這兒呢?
God. Patrick. Why here ?
我看到你對我眉目傳情了
I've seen you looking at me.
我感覺到了
I've noticed your...
你火熱的身體
hot body.
別害羞
Don't be shy.
你不知道我等這天等了多久...
You can't imagine how long I've wanted this...
自從亞利桑那州 206的聖誕派對以來
ever since that Christmas party at Arizona 206.
你知道的 那天你戴了條 阿瑪尼紅條紋花呢領帶
You know, the one you were wearing that red-striped paisley Armani tie.
我要你 我也要你
I want you. I want you too.
- 帕特裏克 - 怎麼回事?
- Patrick. - What is it ?
你去哪兒?
Where are you going ?
我要去還幾盤錄像帶
I've gotta return some video tapes.
帕特裏克!
Patrick !
好的 倫敦...
Okay, London the...
- 倫敦 呃 有定房... - 有和保羅·艾倫有關的嗎?
- London, there's, um, a reservation... - Any Paul Allen ?
- 沒有 定了房 但是... - 金葆!
- No. A reservation, but... - Kimball !
我正想跟你談談呢 來我的辦公室吧
I've been wanting to talk with you. Come into my office.
吉恩 你的上衣很漂亮 是馬特斯圖塔嗎?
Jean, great jacket. Matsuta ?
能想起保羅失蹤那晚你在哪兒嗎?
Do you remember where you were the night of Paul's disappearance,
12月20號那天
which was on the 20th of December ?
上帝
God.
我想我可能去還錄像帶了
I guess I was probably returning video tapes.
我和一個名叫薇若妮卡的姑娘有個約會
I had a date with a girl named Veronica.
- 和我聽說的不一樣呀 - 什麼?
- That's not what I've got. - What ?
我聽說的不是這樣的
That's not the information I've received.
唔 等等
Well, I... Wait.
- 你聽說的是怎麼樣的? - 讓我看看
- What information have you received ? - Let me see.
唔...
Well...
- 你和... - 嗯 我可能記錯了
- You were with... - Well, I could be wrong.
你最後一次見保羅·艾倫是什麼時候?
When was the last time you were with Paul Allen ?
我們一同去聽一個音樂劇
We'd gone to a new musical...
叫"哦 非洲 勇敢的非洲"
called Oh, Africa, Brave Africa.
是出笑鬧劇 就這樣
It was a laugh riot. That was about it.
我想我們在奧搜餐廳吃了晚飯 不 披頭... 不 奧搜餐廳
I think we had dinner at Orso's. No, Peto... No, Orso's.
我希望能對你有所幫助 日子久了 記憶有點混亂
I hope I've been informative. Long day, a bit scattered.
我現在也精疲力盡了
I'm a little spent now too.
過一個星期左右吃頓午飯怎麼樣?
But how about lunch in a week or so...
等我把這些頭緒理清之後
when I've sorted out all this information ?
好極了 是的 我很願意
Great. Yes, I'd like that.
如果我能確定你到底在哪兒
And if you could try and pin down where you were...
在保羅·艾倫失蹤那晚 我的活就好幹多了
the night of Paul Allen's disappearance, it would make my job a lot easier.
當然 我會跟你一起努力回憶的
Absolutely. I'm with you on that one.
休伊 劉易斯 & News
Huey Lewis and the News.
好東西 我在來這兒的路上買的 你聽過嗎?
Great stuff. I just bought it on my way here. You heard it ?
從來沒有 我的意思是我不喜歡流行歌手
Never. I mean, I don't really like singers.
- 不是個樂迷 是吧? - 我喜歡音樂
- Not a big music fan, huh ? - No, I like music.
因為他們...休伊的歌對我來說太灰調了
Just they're... Huey's too black sounding for me.
各有所好
To each his own.
那麼 下週一起吃午飯?
So, lunch next week ?
我會去的
I'll be there.
哦!
Oh !
- 復活節前你會給我打電話嗎? - 也許吧
- Will you call me before Easter ? - Maybe.
你今晚幹什麼?
What are you doing tonight ?
呃 在河畔餐廳吃飯
Dinner at, uh, River Cafe.
- 然後去酒吧 也許 - 不錯
- Au Bar afterwards, maybe. - That's nice.
我還不知道你也抽煙呢
I never knew you smoked.
你沒留心罷了
You never noticed.
聽著 帕特裏克
Listen, Patrick.
我們能談談嗎?
Can we talk ?
你看起來...帥極了
You look... marvelous.
沒什麼好談的
There's nothing to say.
- 你馬上要嫁給拉西了 - 這難道不值一提?
- You're gonna marry Luis. - Isn't that special ?
帕特裏克
Patrick ?
什麼事 考特妮?
Yes, Courtney ?
如果我在復活節前見不到你
If I don't see you before Easter,
你自己玩得開心點 好嗎?
have a nice one, okay ?
你也是
You too.
帕特裏克?
Patrick ?
嗯?
Yeah ?
沒什麼
Nothing.
" Pump up the volume "
現在有個說法... 聽我說
There is this theory now... Listen to me.
現在有個說法說 如果你因為和艾滋病人做愛
There is this theory now that if you can catch the AIDS virus...
而染上艾滋病 那麼你就有可能得任何一種病
by having sex with someone who's infected, then you can catch anything.
老年癡呆 肌肉萎縮 血友病
Alzheimer's, muscular dystrophy, hemophilia,
白血病 糖尿病 失語癥
leukemia, diabetes, dyslexia.
我不敢肯定 但我不認為 失語癥是病毒引起的
I'm not sure, but I don't think dyslexia is a virus.
可誰知道呢? 他們才不知道呢
But who knows ? They don't know that.
證明給我看
Prove it.
- 我 上帝 - 怎麼了?
- Oh, God. - What ?
這簡直就是一小堆甜粉 我是要用它來爽的
It's a fucking milligram of sweetener. I wanna get high off this,
- 不是把它灑在我他媽的燕麥粥上 - 確實弱得可憐
- not sprinkle it on my fucking oatmeal. - It's definitely weak,
但我想如果我們多來點 也許會好些
but I have a feeling if we do enough of it, we'll be okay.
你們能小聲點嗎? 我在嗑藥呢
Can you keep it down ? I'm trying to do drugs.
- 去你的! - 別激動 我們就這麼來吧
- Fuck you ! - Calm down. Let's do it anyway.
這就對了
That's right.
如果隔壁的基佬覺得好就行了!
That is if the faggot in the next stall thinks it's okay !
- 去你的! - 嘿 去你的!
- Fuck you ! - Hey, fuck you !
對不起 哥兒們 激素的作用
Sorry, dude. Steroids.
好了 我們來吧
Okay, let's do it.
" I wanna know "
" What you're thinking "
" There are some things you can't hide "
" I wanna know "
" What you're feeling "
" Tell me what's on your mind "
克雷格去哪兒了?
Where did Craig go ?
嗯 戈爾巴喬夫在樓下 麥克德莫特去跟他簽
Well, Gorbachev is downstairs. McDermott went to sign a peace treaty...
美俄和平協議去了
between the United States and Russia.
他是公開化政策的幕後策劃人
He's the one behind Glasnost.
- 他說他做的是股權的併購和重組 - 你們搞錯了 是吧?
- He said he was in mergers and acquisitions. - You're not confused, are you ?
沒有 怎麼會
No, not really.
- 戈爾巴喬夫不在樓下 - 克倫說得對
- Gorbachev is not downstairs. - Karen's right.
戈爾巴喬夫是不在樓下 他在隧道裏
Gorbachev's not downstairs. He's at Tunnel.
問我個問題吧
Ask me a question.
好吧 你是幹什麼的?
So, what do you do ?
我是 呃 基本上在 和殺人犯和死刑打交道
I'm into, uh, well, murders and executions, mostly.
- 你喜歡這活嗎? - 唔 這要看情況 幹嗎這麼問?
- Do you like it ? - Well, it depends. Why ?
唔 我認識的那些做股票的傢伙 都不喜歡玩股票
Well, most guys I know who work in mergers and acquisitions really don't like it.
好吧 你怎麼猜到的?
So, where do you work out ?
你不會認為我真的很笨吧?
You think I'm dumb, don't you ?
- 什麼? - 你認為我很笨 你認為所有的模特都是笨蛋
- What ? - You think I'm dumb. You think all models are dumb.
不 我才不呢
No. I really don't.
那沒什麼 我不在乎
That's okay. I don't mind.
你挺討人喜歡的
There's something sweet about you.
在玩填字遊戲?
Doin' the crossword ?
要我幫忙嗎?
You need any help ?
- 吉恩? - 什麼事 帕特裏克?
-Jean ? - Yes, Patrick ?
你能陪我吃頓晚飯嗎?
Would you like to accompany me to dinner ?
我是說 如果你沒事的話
That is, if you're not doing anything.
嗯 不 我沒事 我沒任何安排
Um, no. No, I don't have any plans.
好
Well,
真是太巧了
isn't this a coincidence ?
- 聽著 我們要去哪兒? - 隨你便
- Listen, where should we go ? - Anywhere you want.
我們別管我想去哪兒 你到底想去哪兒?
Let's not think about what I want. How about anywhere you want ?
我不知道 帕特裏克 我沒法做這樣的決定
I don't know, Patrick. I can't make this decision.
快點 你想去哪兒?
Come on. Where do you wanna go ?
不管想去哪兒 告訴我 我會設法安排的
Anywhere you want, just say it. I can get us in anywhere.
那...
What about...
去朵西亞怎麼樣?
Dorsia ?
好
So,
朵西亞是吉恩想去的地方
Dorsia is where Jean wants to go.
唔 我不知道該去哪兒 你想去哪兒我就去哪兒
Well, I don't know. We'll go wherever you wanna go.
朵西亞很好
Dorsia is fine.
是朵西亞嗎?
Dorsia. Yes ?
- 是的 能為我在 呃 今晚9點留兩個座嗎? - 我們的座定完了
- Yeah, can you take two tonight at, oh, let's say 9:00 ? - We're totally booked.
真的嗎? 太好了
Really ? That's great.
- 我是說全定完了 - 9點兩個座? 好極了
- No, I said we are totally booked. - Two at 9:00 ? Perfect.
再會
See ya then.
什麼事?
Yeah ?
你今天...穿得很得體
You're... dressed okay.
- 你沒留姓名 - 他們認識我
- You didn't give a name. - They know me.
能在7點到我家來會面嗎?
Why don't you meet me at my place at 7:00...
喝兩杯
for drinks.
還有 吉恩
And Jean,
我們出去前你最好換身衣服
you'll wanna change before we go out.
帕特裏克 這兒真美
Patrick, it's so elegant.
多好的風景啊
What a wonderful view.
吉恩
Jean,
果汁冰淇淋?
sorbet ?
謝謝 帕特裏克 我想來點
Thanks, Patrick. I'd love some.
- 你不也來點嗎? - 我在節食 不過謝謝你了
- Do you want a bite ? - I'm on a diet. But thank you.
你沒必要減肥 在開玩笑 是嗎?
You don't need to lose any weight. You're kidding, right ?
你體型好極了 很健康
You look great. Very fit.
人總是想再瘦點 看起來更漂亮點
You can always be thinner, look better.
哦 也許我們不該出去吃飯 我不想動搖你的意志
Well, maybe we shouldn't go out to dinner. I don't wanna ruin your will power.
沒事 這沒什麼
No, it's all right.
我本來就控制不住
I'm not very good at controlling it anyway.
聽好
So listen.
你一生真正想幹的是什麼?
What do you really wanna do with your life ?
簡單說說 概括一下
Just briefly, summarize.
還有別跟我說你喜歡 看孩子之類的 好嗎?
And don't tell me you enjoy working with children, okay ?
唔 我想旅遊還有也許會學校唸書
Well, I'd like to travel and maybe go back to school,
但我不能確定
but I don't really know.
我正處在最多選擇的人生階段
I'm at a point in my life where there seems to be so many possibilities,
可我...我不知道... 我一點也不能確定
but I'm... I don't know... I'm just so unsure.
你有男朋友嗎?
Do you have a boyfriend ?
- 不 沒有 - 有意思
- No, not really. - Interesting.
你有合適的對象嗎? 我是說真的
Are you seeing anyone ? I mean, seriously ?
也許有
Maybe.
我也不知道 真的不知道
I don't know. Not really.
吉恩
Jean,
你有成就感嗎?
do you feel... fulfilled ?
我是說 你這一生?
I mean, in your life ?
我想有點吧 我專心工作已經很長時間了
I guess I do. For a long time I was too focused on my work.
但現在我已經開始 考慮改變自我了 你知道的
But now I've really begun to think about changing myself, you know,
發展一下自我
developing and growing.
發展 很高興聽你這麼說
Growing. I'm glad you said that.
你知道嗎 呃 泰德·邦迪的第一隻狗
Did you know that, uh, Ted Bundy's first dog,
一隻牧羊犬 叫拉西?
a collie, was named Lassie ?
- 你聽說過嗎? - 誰是泰德·邦迪?
- Had you heard this ? - Who's Ted Bundy ?
別管他了
Forget it.
那是什麼?
What's that ?
膠帶 我用它來 呃 粘東西
Duct tape. I need it for, uh, taping something.
帕特裏克
Patrick,
你有沒有想過...讓一個人快樂?
have you ever wanted to... make someone happy ?
什麼? 別! 把它放在墊子上
What ? No ! Put it in the carton.
對不起
Sorry.
吉恩?
Jean ?
- 你說什麼? - 呃 讓一個人開心?
- What ? - Uh, make someone happy ?
你有沒有想過?
Have you ever wanted to ?
我在找尋 呃
I'm looking for, uh,
我想應該說我只想和某些特殊的人
I guess you could say I just wanna have a meaningful relationship...
保持良好的關係
with someone special. Hmm.
帕特裏克? 帕特裏克? 我知道你在那兒
Patrick ? Patrick ? I know you're there.
快接電話 你這個壞小子
Pick up the phone, you badboy.
你今晚要幹什麼? 是我 別想躲開我
What are you up to tonight ? It's me. Don't try to hide.
希望你不是在和什麼路邊找來的女兒鬼混 因為你是我的巴特曼先生
I hope you're not with some little number you picked up because you're my Mr. Bateman.
我的鄰家男孩
My boy next door.
不管怎麼說你一個電話也沒給我打 儘管你答應過的
Anyway, you never called me and you said you would,
我還要給吉恩也留個言 讓她提醒你
and I'll leave a message for Jean about this, too, to remind you,
可我們得和梅拉尼亞和泰勒吃飯
but we're having dinner with Melania and Taylor.
你知道梅拉尼亞的 她去斯威特-布賴爾了
You know Melania. She went to Sweet Briar.
我們會在康乃爾俱樂部會面
And we're meeting at the Cornell Club,
我明天早上會給你來電話的 親愛的
so I'll call you tomorrow morning, honey.
哦 抱歉 我知道 你不喜歡這麼叫你
Oops. Sorry. I know you hate that.
再見 帕特裏克 再見 大時代總裁先生 再見
Bye, Patrick. Bye, Mr. Big Time C.E.O. Bye-bye.
是伊芙琳嗎?
Was that Evelyn ?
你還和她約會?
Are you still seeing her?
對不起 我沒權這麼問
I'm sorry. I have no right to ask that.
你要我離開嗎?
Do you want me to go ?
是的
Yeah.
我想我會控制不住自己的
I don't think I can control myself.
我明白 我該離開的 我知道我總會和得不到的男人糾纏不清
I know. I should go. I know I have a tendency to get involved with unavailable men.
我是說
I mean,
你真要我走嗎?
do you want me to go ?
我想如果你留下來
I think if you stay,
就會發生一些不好的事
something bad will happen.
我想我會傷害你的
I think I might hurt you.
你不想受到傷害 是嗎?
You don't wanna get hurt, do you ?
不 當然不
No. No, I guess not.
我不想被打得鼻青臉腫的
I don't wanna get bruised.
說的沒錯 你是該走了
You're right. I should go.
哦 別忘了你明天中午要和唐納德 金葆 在史密斯 & Wolenski餐廳吃飯
Oh. Don't forget you have a lunch date tomorrow with Donald Kimball at Smith and Wolenski's.
謝謝
Thanks.
這事我都忘光了
It slipped my mind completely.
他失蹤的那晚...
So, the night he disappeared...
你想起你幹了什麼了嗎?
any new thoughts about what you did ?
還是不能確定 唔 我沖了個澡
Not sure. Um, I had a shower...
吃了果汁冰淇淋?
and some sorbet ?
我想你把約會的人搞錯了
I think you're getting your dates mixed up.
怎麼會呢?
But how ?
你說那天晚上...保羅在哪兒?
Where do you place... Paul that night ?
根據他的記事本 經他的秘書確證
According to his date book, and this was verified by his secretary,
他和馬克斯 海博斯坦姆一起吃的晚飯
he had dinner with Marcus Halberstram.
- 還有呢? - 我詢問了他
- And ? - I questioned him.
- 馬克斯嗎? - 是的 他否認了這點 儘管一開始他也不能確定
- Marcus ? - Yes, and he denies it, though, at first, he couldn't be sure.
- 但他否認了 - 是的
- But he denied it. - Yes.
那麼馬克斯有不在腸證人嗎?
Well, does Marcus have an alibi ?
- 有 - 他有嗎? 你確定?
- Yes. He does ? - You're sure ?
我查過了 沒問題
I checked it out. It's clean.
那麼 你當時在哪兒?
Now, where were you ?
馬克斯在哪兒?
Where was Marcus ?
他沒和保羅·艾倫在一起
He wasn't with Paul Allen.
- 那他和誰在一起? - 他在...
- Who was he with ? - He was...
亞特蘭蒂斯和...
at Atlantis... with...
克雷格·麥克德莫特 弗雷德裏克·迪布爾 哈里·紐曼 喬治...
Craig McDermott, Frederick Dibble, Harry Newman, George Butner...
還有...你在一起
and... you.
哦 對啦 是的 當然如此
Oh, right, yeah. Of course.
我們在等保羅·艾倫來
We had wanted Paul Allen to come,
但他另有安排
but he had made plans.
我想我和維多利亞吃飯是在第二天晚上
And I guess I had dinner with Victoria the following night.
我個兒以為 這傢伙可能惹了點麻煩
Personally, I think the guy went a little nutso.
因此出去避避風頭 也許他真去倫敦了 去閒逛喝酒什麼的
Split town for a while. Maybe he did go to London, sightseeing, drinking, whatever.
不管怎麼說 我相信他遲早會現身的 我的意思是 認為
Anyway, I'm pretty sure he'll turn up sooner or later. I mean, to think...
他被他的某個朋友莫名其妙地殺了 無論如何有點可笑
that one of his friends killed him for no reason whatsoever would be too ridiculous.
是這樣嗎 帕特裏克?
Isn't that right, Patrick ?
克利斯蒂 克利斯蒂
Christie. Christie.
我不知道我該不該去 上次出來我就進急診室了
I'm not so sure about this. I had to go to Emergency after last time.
這次絕對不會像上次那樣了 我保證
This won't be anything like last time. I promise.
我不相信
I don't think so.
快上車吧 我們就談一分鐘
Just come in the limo and talk to me for a minute.
司機在這兒呢 你很安全的
The driver's here. You'll be safe.
絕對不會像上次那樣 我保證
Nothing like last time. Promise.
好吧
All right.
嗯 你看起來很美 最近怎麼樣?
So, you're looking great. How have you been ?
- 實際上我上次差點都要動手術了 - 真的嗎?
- Well, I actually might need surgery after last time. - Really ?
我朋友甚至跟我說我應該請個律師
My friend told me I should maybe even get a lawyer.
律師太麻煩了
Lawyers are so complicated.
別聽她的
Don't do that.
這兒有張支票
Here's a check.
呃 現在一半 完事另一半
Uh-uh. Half now, half later.
好吧 你就叫克利斯蒂
Okay, your name is Christie.
我們要和我的一個朋友 伊麗莎白會面
We're meeting a friend of mine, Elizabeth.
她馬上就會到我的新公寓來的
She'll be joining us in my new apartment shortly.
你會喜歡她的 她是個很好的姑娘
You'll like her. She's a very nice girl.
你看起來真面熟 到過道爾頓嗎?
You look really familiar. Did you go to Dalton ?
我想我在"衝浪"酒吧遇到過你 對不對? 和史派西在一起?
I think I met you at Surf Bar, didn't I ? With Spicey ?
唔 也許不是和史派西 但肯定在"衝浪"酒吧 你知道的 "衝浪"酒吧
Well, maybe not with Spicey, but definitely at SurfBar. You know, SurfBar.
不管怎麼說 "衝浪"酒吧現在糟透了 真糟
Anyway, Surf Bar sucks now. It's terrible.
到那兒去參加馬爾科姆·福布斯的生日派對 哦 上帝啊 饒了我吧
Went to a birthday party there for Malcolm Forbes. Oh, my God, please.
這比你另外那個公寓還要好
This is nicer than your other apartment.
哦 沒那麼誇張
Oh, it's not that nice.
- 你們兩個怎麼認識的? - 哦 上帝 我們在...
- Where did you two meet ? - Oh, God. We met at...
哦 上帝 肯德基的德比認識的 85或者86年
oh, God, at the Kentucky Derby in '85, or '86.
你那時候和那個淫蕩的阿利森·普爾混在一起 真是個風騷貨
You were hanging out with that bimbo Allison Poole. Hot number.
你什麼意思? 她不是風騷貨
What do you mean ? She was a hot number.
只要你有白金卡 她就給你做口交 這娘們在日光沙龍幹 你知道的
If you had a platinum card, she'd give you a blowjob. This girl worked in a tanning salon.
你幹哪行的?
What do you do ?
她是...我侄女
She's my... cousin.
- 呃 - 她從...巴黎來
- Uh-huh. - She's from... France.
你的電話呢? 我得給哈雷打個電話
Where's your phone ? I've gotta call Harley.
你在哪兒度暑假 南漢普頓?
Where do you summer, South Hampton ?
- 不 - 哦 上帝 是他的留言機
- No. - Oh, God, it's his machine.
- 現在是凌晨3點 - 他是賣藥的 現在生意正好呢
- It's 3:00 in the morning. - He's a goddamn drug dealer. These are his peak hours.
- 別告訴你在這兒 - 我怎麼會呢?
- Don't tell him you're here. - Why would I ?
這味道真怪
This tastes weird.
哈雷 是我 我需要你的服務 隨你怎麼理解這意思
Harley, it's me. I need your services. Translate that however you want.
- 我在... - 保羅·艾倫家
- I'm at... - Paul Allen's.
- 誰? - 保羅·艾倫家
- Who ? - Paul Allen's.
我要那玩意兒 笨蛋 不管怎麼說 我在保羅·諾曼家 一會兒再給你打
I want the number, idiot. Anyway, I'm at Paul Norman's and I'll try you again later.
要是明晚在坎奈爾酒吧看不到你 我就會讓我的理髮師找你算帳
And if I don't see you at Canal Bar tomorrow night I'm gonna sic my hairdresser on you.
你認識那個失蹤的傢伙嗎?
Did you know that guy who disappeared ?
他不也在P&P工作嗎? 他是你朋友嗎?
Didn't he work at Pierce & Pierce ? Was he a friend of yours ?
不是
No.
你有可樂嗎? 或者翡翠屬?
Do you have any coke ? Or Halcyon ?
- 我想來杯翡翠屬 - 聽著
- I would take a Halcyon. - Listen.
我只想看看
I would just like to see...
你們兩個...幹起來
the two of you... get it on.
有什麼不妥嗎?
What's wrong with that ?
肯定不會染上病的
It's totally disease free.
- 帕特裏克 你瘋了 - 來吧
- Patrick, you're a lunatic. -Come on.
你不認為克利斯蒂很吸引人嗎?
Don't you find Christie attractive ?
別來色的 我沒心情講葷段子
Let's not get lewd. I'm in no mood for a lewd conversation.
來吧
Come on.
- 我覺得這很讓人興奮 - 他老這麼幹嗎?
- I think it'd be a turn-on. - Does he do this all the time ?
克利斯蒂 你沒喝你的酒
Christie, you're not drinking your wine.
你是說你從來沒和女的搞過?
Are you telling me you've never gotten it on with a girl?
沒有 我不是同性戀
No. I'm not a lesbian.
你為什麼認為我會幹這個?
Why would you think I would be into that ?
唔 你去找薩拉·勞倫斯就為了一件事
Well, you went to Sarah Lawrence for one thing.
那些是薩拉·勞倫斯那幫傢伙幹的 你讓我感覺怪怪的
Those are Sarah Lawrence guys, Patrick. You're making me feel weird.
你知道
Did you know...
惠特尼·休斯頓的首張密紋唱片
that Whitney Houston's debut LP...
叫做《簡單的惠特尼休斯頓》
called simply Whitney Houston...
包含了四首第一流的單曲?
had four number-one singles on it ?
你知道嗎 克利斯蒂?
Did you know that, Christie ?
你到底聽不聽惠特尼休斯頓的歌?
You actually listen to Whitney Houston ?
你有她的CD嗎?
You own a Whitney Houston CD ?
不止一張?
More than one ?
這麼多精彩的曲目裏挑最好的相當困難
It's hard to choose a favorite among so many great tracks.
但這首《最偉大的愛》 是有史以來
But the "Greatest Love Of All" is one of the best, most powerful songs...
最好最勁的歌曲之一
ever written...
關於自我尊嚴的維護
about self-preservation...and dignity.
這事跨越國界的全球之聲
It's universal message crosses all boundaries...
並且潛移默化地 把這樣一個希望告訴人們
and instills one...
現在開始改善自我
with the hope that it's not too late...
還不算太晚
to better ourselves.
因為 伊麗莎白
Since, Elizabeth,
在我們生活的這個世界 和別人同情連心是不可能的
it's impossible in this world we live in to empathize with others,
但我們總能和自己同情連心吧
we can always empathize with ourselves.
這是很重要的一點 確實至關重要
It's an important message. Crucial, really.
而它通過這張專集優美地傳達出來
And it's beautifully stated on the album.
竟敢打我的臉!
Not the face !
臭婊子 竟敢打我的臉 你這個臭婊子!
You bitch, not the fucking face, you piece of bitch trash !
我想要一個確定的承諾
I want a firm commitment.
我想 呃 伊芙琳 我們已經沒什麼共同語言了
I think, um, Evelyn, that, uh, we've lost touch.
為什麼? 怎麼了?
Why ? What's wrong ?
我瘋狂嗜殺的渴求
My need to engage in homicidal behavior...
無法遏制
on a massive scale cannot be corrected,
但除此之外再沒什麼可以滿足我的渴求
but I have no other way to fulfill my needs.
- 我們得好好談談 - 談什麼 帕特裏克?
- We need to talk. - Talk about what, Patrick ?
我們完了 伊芙琳
It's over, Evelyn.
一切都完了
It's all over.
別激動 別激動 我很抱歉又提起結婚的事
Touchy, touchy. I'm sorry I brought up the wedding.
我們不談這個了 好嗎? 好 來杯咖啡嗎?
Let's just avoid the issue, all right ? Now, are we having coffee ?
我是認真的 我們已經完了 不是開玩笑
I'm fucking serious. It's fucking over, us. This is no joke.
呃 我想我們以後都別再見面了
Uh, I don't think we should see each other anymore.
可是你的朋友也是我的朋友 我的朋友也是你的朋友
But your friends are my friends and my friends are your friends.
我想這是不可能的 你是不是有點...
I really don't think it would work. You have a little something...
我知道你的朋友也是我的朋友 並且 呃 我都想過了
I know that your friends are my friends, and, uh... and I've thought about that.
你還可以繼續和他們交往
You can have 'em.
- 你是當真的 是嗎? - 是的
- You're really serious, aren't you ? - Yes, lam.
- 那我們過去的一切呢? - 我們根本沒有什麼過去
- What about the past ? Our past ? - We never really shared one.
- 你真冷血 - 不
- You're inhuman. - No.
我很有人情味
I'm in touch with humanity.
伊芙琳 我 呃 很抱歉 我只是 呃...
Evelyn, I'm, uh, sorry. I just, uh...
你對我而言並不很重要
You're not terribly important to me.
哦 不!
Oh, no !
不 不 帕特裏克
No. No, Patrick.
我知道我有時候... 行事古怪
I know my behavior can be... erratic sometimes.
你想讓我怎麼樣? 你到底想怎麼樣?
What do you want me to do ? What is it that you want ?
如果你真想為我做點什麼 現在就別這樣惹人注目
If you really wanna do something for me, then stop making this scene right now.
哦 上帝 我真不敢相信
Oh, God, I can't believe this.
我要走了 我把事情都說清楚了 我該走了
I'm leaving. I've assessed the situation, and I'm going.
- 你要去哪兒? - 我要走了
- Where are you going ? - I'm just leaving.
可去哪兒?
But where ?
我得去還幾盤錄像帶
I have to return some videotapes.
來 小貓咪
Here, kitty, kitty.
哦 上帝 你在幹嗎?
Oh, my God. What are you doing ?
住手
Stop that.
放下武器! 馬上放下!
Drop the weapon ! Drop it now !
趴下來! 把你的...
Get on the ground! Put your...
熬夜加班嗎 史密斯先生?
Burning the midnight oil, Mr. Smith ?
嘿 別忘了簽字
Hey, now don't forget to sign in.
霍華德 我是巴特曼 帕特裏克·巴特曼
Howard, it's Bateman. Patrick Bateman.
你是我的律師 因為我想你該知道我殺了很多人
You're my lawyer, so I think you should know I've killed a lot of people.
在新城區的一間公寓裏 殺了幾個三陪女郎
Some escort girls in an apartment uptown,
呃 幾個流浪漢 也許五或十個
uh, some homeless people, maybe five or ten,
中央公園碰到的一個紐約女大學生
an N.Y.U. girl I met in Central Park.
我把她扔在某家炸餅店 後面的停車場了
I left her at a parking lot behind some doughnut shop.
我用釘槍殺了波扎妮 我以前的女朋友
I killed Bethany, my old girlfriend, with a nail gun.
還有 還有 還有別的幾個人 一些牽著狗的老蘆柴棒
And-And-And then some man, s-s-some old faggot with a dog.
上星期 我 呃...
Last week, I, uh...
我用一把電鋸殺了另一個姑娘
I killed another girl with a chain saw.
我是迫不得已的 她差點就溜了
I had to. She almost got away.
還有...
And...
其他一些 我記不起來了 也許是模特...她也死了
Someone else there. I can't remember, maybe a model... She's dead too.
還有 呃 保羅·艾倫
And, uh, Paul Allen.
我用一把斧頭劈開了他的臉
I killed Paul Allen with an ax in the face.
他的屍體在地獄廚房的浴缸裏腐爛著呢
His body is dissolving in a bathtub in Hell's Kitchen.
我不想在這裏留下任何東西 我想我大概殺了...二十個人
I don't wanna leave anything out here. I guess I've killed maybe... 20 people.
也許四十!
Maybe 40 !
我把很多都錄下來了
I have tapes of a lot of it.
有些姑娘還看過這些帶子
Some of the girls have seen the tapes.
我甚至 呃
I even, um,
吃了一些他們的腦子
I ate some of their brains...
我想試試做點菜
and I tried to cook a little.
今晚 我 呃...
Tonight, I, uh...
我被迫殺了很多很多人!
I just had to kill a lot of people !
並且 嗯
And, um,
我想我逃不掉了...這回
I'm not sure I'm gonna get away with it... this time.
因此 呃...我是說
So, uh... I mean,
我想...
I guess...
我是個相當 呃...
I'm a pretty, uh...
我是說 我想 我是個很變態的傢伙
I mean, I guess I'm a pretty sick guy.
好
So,
如果你明天回來了
if you get back tomorrow,
我也許會去哈里酒吧
I may show up at Harry's Bar.
你知道的
So, you know,
保持清醒
keep your eyes open.
好了
Okay.
哦!
Oh !
你是在赴我2點鐘約會的嗎?
Are you my 2:00 ?
- 不 - 我能為你效勞嗎?
- No. - Can I help you ?
我在找...保羅·艾倫的家
I'm looking for... Paul Allen's place.
- 他...不是住這兒嗎? - 不 他不住這兒
- Doesn't he... live here ? - No, he doesn't.
你肯定嗎?
You sure ?
你是在時代週刊上看到了廣告?
You saw the ad in the Times ?
不 是的 我是說 是的
No. Yeah. I mean, yeah.
- 在時代週刊上 - 我根本沒在時代週刊上登過廣告
- In the Times. - There was no ad in the Times.
我想你該離開這兒了
I think you should go now.
可我想...
But I think...
我想知道這裏發生了什麼事?
I wanna know what happened here.
請你別惹麻煩
Don't make any trouble, please.
我建議你馬上走
I suggest you go.
別回來
Don't come back.
我不會的
I won't.
別擔心
Don't worry.
帕特裏克·巴特曼辦公室
Patrick Bateman's office.
- 吉恩? 我需要你的幫助 - 帕特裏克 是你嗎?
- Jean ? I need help. - Patrick, is that you ?
吉恩 我不...
Jean, I'm not...
克雷格 麥克德莫特來電說想和你 大衛·范·派頓和提姆·布瑞斯在哈里酒吧會面
Craig McDermott called. Wants to meet you, David Van Patten and Tim Bryce at Harry's.
哦 上帝 你在說什麼呀 蠢娘們?
Oh, God. What did you say, you dumb bitch ?
- 帕特裏克 我聽不清你在說什麼 - 我在幹什麼呀?
- Patrick, I can't hear you. - What am I doing ?
你在哪兒 帕特裏克? 出什麼事了?
Where are you, Patrick ? What's wrong ?
我想我不能 吉恩 去 呃
I don't think I'm gonna make it, Jean, to the, uh,
辦公室了 今天下午
office this afternoon.
為什麼?
Why ?
- 我說了不行 - 怎麼了 帕特裏克? 你沒事吧?
- Just say no ! - What is it, Patrick ? Are you all right ?
別裝出那麼難過的樣子了
Stop sounding so fucking sad.
天哪!
Jesus !
- 這是三個人的座位 - 巴特曼 你看來很不高興 今天過得不好嗎?
- That's a table for three. - Bateman, you're looking wild-eyed. Rough day ?
嘿 看 布瑞斯回來了 他在喝礦泉水
Hey, look. Bryce is back and he's drinking mineral water.
他大變樣了 可是他還是定不到位子
He's a changed man, except for he still can't a reservation to save his life.
為什麼不去150伍斯特碰碰運氣呢?
Why don't you just try 150 Wooster?
沒定好位子我哪兒也不去
I'm not going anywhere unless we have a reservation.
太陽弗拉明戈東牡蠣酒吧 來吧 夥計們 我們去定個座吧
Le Cirque, Flamingo East, Oyster Bar. Come on, faggots. Let's get a "res."
別脫襯衫 好像吊帶鬆了
Keep your shirt on. Maybe lose the suspenders.
定8點半的座
Need a reservation for 8:30.
失陪一會兒 馬上回來
Excuse me, gentlemen. Right back.
10點不行 不行
10:00 would not be any good. No.
快給他們打電話 把電話給我 我來打 我會給你回電的
Just fucking call them. Give me the phone. I'll do it. I'll call you back.
面對現實吧 日本人在九十年代末 就會壟斷這個國家的大部分財富了
Face it. The Japanese will own most of this country by the end of the '90s.
閉嘴 卡恩斯 他們別想
Shut up, Carnes. They will not.
嗯 哈羅德 你聽到我的留言了嗎?
So, uh, Harold, did you get my message ?
天哪 聽到了 真夠搞笑的 其實是你留的 對吧?
Jesus, yes. That was hilarious. That was you, wasn't it ?
- 是啊 自然是 - 巴特曼殺了艾倫還有三陪女
- Yeah, naturally. - Bateman killing Allen and the escort girls.
- 真有趣 夠好玩 - 你到底什麼意思?
- That's fabulous. That's rich. - What exactly do you mean ?
你的留言啊 順便問一下 戴維斯·辛西婭好嗎? 你還和她約會 是嗎?
The message you left. By the way, Davis, how's Cynthia ? You're still seeing her, right ?
等等 哈羅德 你什麼意思啊?
W-Wait, Harold. What do you mean ?
抱歉 沒什麼 很高興見到你
Excuse me. Nothing. It's good to see you.
那是愛德華·塔沃斯嗎?
Is that Edward Towers?
卡恩斯 等等 呃...
Carnes, wait. Uh...
戴維斯 我不會到處亂講的 你的玩笑開得夠水平
Davis, I'm not one to bad-mouth anyone. Your joke was amusing.
但是 朋友 你犯了個致命的錯誤
But come on, man. You had one fatal flaw:
巴特曼膽小如鼠
Bateman is such a dork.
無聊 沒骨氣 還沒肌肉
Such a boring, spineless lightweight.
如果你說是布瑞斯或者麥克德莫特幹的話... 不管怎麼說 很搞笑
Now, if you said Bryce or Mc Dermott. Otherwise, it was amusing.
請恕我失陪 我真的得走了
Now, if you'll excuse me, I really must be going.
等等 呃...站住
Wait. Uh... Stop.
我真的幹了 卡恩斯
I did it, Carnes.
我殺了他
I killed him.
我是帕特裏克·巴特曼
I'm Patrick Bateman.
我把艾倫的頭砍下來了
I chopped Allen's fucking head off.
我在留言裏說的都是實話
The whole message I left on your machine was true.
抱歉 我真的得走了
Excuse me. I really must be going now.
不 不 聽著
No. No, listen.
你還不知道我是誰嗎?
Don't you know who I am ?
我不是戴維斯 我就是帕特裏克·巴特曼
I'm not Davis. I'm Patrick Bateman.
我們常在電話上聊天的
We talk on the phone all the time.
你認不出我來了嗎?
Don't you recognize me ?
你是我的律師
You're my lawyer.
現在 卡恩斯 聽我說
Now, Carnes, listen.
給我仔細聽著
Listen very, very carefully.
我殺了保羅·艾倫
I killed Paul Allen,
我喜歡這麼幹
and I liked it.
我說得再清楚不過了
I can't make myself any clearer.
可這根本不可能 而且我也不覺得這有趣了
But that's simply not possible. And I don't find this funny anymore.
這絕不是編出來的 為什麼不可能?
It never was supposed to be. Why isn't it possible ?
- 就是不可能 - 為什麼 你這個蠢貨?
- It's just not. - Why not, you stupid bastard ?
因為我和保羅·艾倫剛吃過兩次飯
Because I had dinner with Paul Allen...
10天前在倫敦
twice in London just ten days ago.
不 你...
No, you...
- 不可能的 - 現在恕我失陪了
- didn't. Now, - if you'll excuse me.
我們已經看到了相互猜忌的惡果
We've seen the results of that mistrust...
各州政府間相互欺騙 相互交易
in the form of lies, provisions in the states.
當我們意識到外交政策 不能光由一個委員會制定
We need to find a way to cooperate while realizing foreign policy...
我們必須找到一條相互合作的道路
can't be run by committee.
而且我相信越來越多的人開始認識到
And I believe there's now the growing sense...
相互合作會讓我們事半功倍
that we can accomplish more by cooperating.
而最終 這將是對已反伊朗事件面目出現的
And in the end, this maybe the eventual blessing in disguise...
混亂局面順利解決的最好祝福
to come out of the Iran-Contra mess.
他怎麼能這樣瞪著眼睛撒謊?
How can he lie like that ?
- 他怎麼能放這種屁? - 放什麼屁?
- How can he pull that shit ? - What shit ?
好了 你們在哪兒定了座?
Now, where do we have reservations at ?
我不餓 可我想在什麼地方定個位子
I'm not really hungry, but I'd like to have reservations someplace.
你怎麼能這麼...
How can you be so fucking,
我不知道該怎麼說 對此這麼冷血?
I don't know, cool about it ?
有些人生來冷血 我想
Some guys are just born cool, I guess.
巴特曼?
Bateman ?
- 你在樂什麼呀? - 我是個快樂的露營者
- What are you so fucking zany about ? - I'm just a happy camper.
快樂的不得了!
Rockin' and a rollin' !
哦 弟兄們 看呀
Oh, brother, look.
他做出一副無辜的老頭的樣子 可是骨子裏...
He presents himself as this harmless old codger, but inside...
可是骨子裏...
but inside...
可是骨子裏毫無所謂
But inside doesn't matter.
骨子裏怎麼樣? 相信嗎 布瑞斯 我們真在聽你說呢
Inside ? Believe or not, Bryce, we're actually listening to you.
來吧 巴特曼 你怎麼認為?
Come on, Bateman. What do you think ?
- 無所謂 - 誰出的餿主意要的乾啤?
- Whatever. - Whose moronic idea was it to order dry beers ?
我要蘇格蘭威士忌
I need a scotch.
再沒有什麼障礙需要逾越
There are no more barriers to cross.
所有桀傲不馴者 精神錯亂者 作奸犯科者所共有的不安
All I have in common with the uncontrollable and the insane,
所有我犯過的罪行造成的傷害
the vicious and the evil, all the mayhem I have caused...
以及我對這一切的漠視
and my utter indifference toward it,
我現在都成功逾越了
I have now surpassed.
我的痛苦恆久而深切
My pain is constant and sharp...
我不希望世界為任何人變得更好
and I do not hope for a better world for anyone.
實際上 我要把我的痛苦加諸別人的身上
In fact, I want my pain to be inflicted on others.
我不希望誰能倖免
I want no one to escape.
可即使我坦言相陳
But even after admitting this,
我依然沒有得以疏解
there is no catharsis.
我無法逃脫我的罪罰
My punishment continues to elude me...
我也不能再更深地認識自我
and I gain no deeper knowledge of myself.
我所說的再無新意可挖
No new knowledge can be extracted from my telling.
這番自白因此...毫無意義
This confession has meant... nothing.
" Abracadoo "
" I lose you "
" We can't avoid the ciash "
" The big mistake "
" Now we're gonna pay and pay "
" I guess you know I never wanted anyone "
" More than you "
" Lived all our best times "
" But I know you'll hoId your head up high "
" There's nothing we have to say "
" There is nothing in our eyes "
" But there's something in the air "
" Something I have to say "
" There's something in the air "
Word " Who feels it "
" Loves it "
" Who knows it "
" Shows it "
" Who feeIs it "
" Knows it "
" Who Ioves it "
" Shows it "
" Who feels it "
" Loves it "
" Who knows it "
" Shows it "
"Come on So what you gonna do with a broken heart "
" What you gonna do when they put you down "
" Move to the hip groove underground "
" What you gonna do when you miss your mark "
" Chill out Choose a brand- new start "
" How does it feel to be back on top "
" It's good, uh- huh And you don't stop "
" Who feels it "
" Knows it "
" Who loves it "
" Shows it "
" Who feels it "
" Loves it "
" Who knows it "
" Yeah, I've been watching me fall "
" For it seems like years "
" Watching me grow small "
" I watch me "
" Disappear "
" Slipping out my ordinary world "
" Out of my or diaries "
" I'm watching me "
" Scream "
" Fall "